Guide to the Office of the President, Yale University, Gifts Received
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Office of the president, Yale University, gifts received
1960-2008
RU 393
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
41.27
(21 boxes)
The records consist of letters, maps, scrapbooks, works of art, and other assorted objects given to the president of Yale University as gifts. Included are gifts received from the president of Wuhan University in the People's Republic of China, Moscow State University, Famille Aycardi Archives, and the American Association of Teachers of Spanish and Portuguese.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-A (YRG 2-A), Records of the Yale president's office.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of letters, maps, scrapbooks, works of art, and other assorted objects given to the president of Yale University as gifts. Included are gifts received from the president of Wuhan University in the People's Republic of China, Moscow State University, Famille Aycardi Archives, and the American Association of Teachers of Spanish and Portuguese.
Gifts; Yale University. President's Office
- Posters and prints received by A. Bartlett Giamatti during his tenure as President of Yale University, 1978-1986; Accession 19ND-A-425 (Box 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
- Gift book from Tsao Shiam-jye concerning research on the ancient culture of China, undated; Accession 1984-A-057
  - Gift book from Tsao Shiam-jye concerning research on the ancient culture of China, undated (Box 1)
- Gifts to the president, Accession 1986-A-109
  - Infrared photo of New Haven, given by the alumni of the School of Engineering (Box 1)
  - Greeting form the World Association of Industrial & technological Research Organizations (Box 2)
  - Greeting from the President & faculty from the Ultraiectinae University (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President and Faculty from Basilientsis University. (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President from Albert….? University (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President from the Iena Litterarum University (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President from the Novi Porkus University (Hungary) (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President from the Kiel University (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President from Cornelle University (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President and Faculty from the Senate of the University of St. Andrews. Dedication the Sterling Chemistry Laboratories (Box 2)
  - Greetings to the President and Faculty from the Rector and the Senate of the University of Frederic Halen (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President and Faculty from the Senate of the University of Upsalen (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President and Faculty from the University of Edinburg (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President from the Senate of the University of Holmien (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President and Faculty from the College Committee of the United Free Church of Scotland. (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President and Fellows from the Johns Hopkins University (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President and Faculty from the Senate of the University of Glasgow (Box 2)
  - SheffieldScientific School. Resolutions of the Sheffield Memorial Meeting, 1882 February 21 (Box 2)
  - Greeting to the President and Faculty from Princeton University (Box 3)
- Gifts received from Moscow State University, circa 1986; Accession 1987-A-052
  - Gifts received from Moscow State University, circa 1986 (Box 1)
- Gifts received from the president of Wuhan University, 1986; Accession 1987-A-058
  - Gifts received from the president of Wuhan University, 1986 (Box 1)
- Copies of maps, letters, ships, buses, memorials, proclamations, paintings, and other items from the "Famillie Aycardi Archives", 1998; Accession 1998-A-114 (Box 1)
- 2 lithographs based upon the writings of L. Ron Hubbard, 1987-1988; Accession 2001-A-138
  - 2 lithographs based upon the writings of L. Ron Hubbard, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
- Mounted prints presented to A. Whitney Griswold, 1960; Accession 2001-A-176
  - Mounted prints presented to A. Whitney Griswold, 1960 (Box 1)
- Gifts given to President Levin during his trip to China celebrating Yale's tercentennial, 2001; Accession 2002-A-032
  - Glass Building - China Public Radio (Box 1)
  - Business Card Holder - Ningbo Education Committee (Box 1)
  - Picture - Masks/faces - Mayor of Shanghai (Box 1)
  - Picture of Fudan University - Fudan University (Box 1)
  - Plastic Plate - Hunan University (Box 1)
  - Postcard package from the Lucoral Museum and six compact disks in a gift bag from Lucoral & Lupearl Group, with business card of Dah-Kuen Shieh attached (Box 1)
  - Ningbo University brochure, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Lapel Pin - Fudan University logo - Fudan University (Box 1)
  - 2 Guanghua School of Management, Peking University catalogs, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Peking University Education Foundation information packet and Peking University gift bag (empty), 2001 (Box 1)
  - Dunhuang Symphony - commemorative bookplates of the Centennial Anniversary (2) (Box 1)
  - Large Ceramic Plate - Ningbo Education Commission (Box 2)
    Item is permanently restricted due to physical condition.
  - Floral sculpture (jade?) in silk lined box (Box 3)
  - Red and Green Vase in silk lined box from Peking University (Box 4)
  - Scrolls
    - Hunan-style scrolls from Yali Middle School
      - Dragon and bird (Box 5)
      - Bird in tree (Box 6)
      - Pandas (Box 7)
    - Monkey smelling flower -from Xiaoshi Middle School, Ningbo (Box 8)
- Gifts given to President Levin during his trip to Japan and Korea, 2008; Accession 2011-A-065
  - Diploma, Doctor of Laws, Waseda University, 2008 October 16 (Box 1)
  - Diploma, Doctor of Laws, Waseda University (in Japanese), 2008 October 16 (Box 1)
  - World Knowledge Forum certificate, Seoul, Korea, 2008 October 16 (Box 1)
  - Black lacquer box, gift from Waseda University, 2008 October 16 (Box 1)
  - Honorary Doctorate, University of Tokyo (English and Japanese translations), 2008 October 17 (Box 1)
  - Citation ["Waseda's first ever Yale University Day"] in English and Japanese, Waseda University, 2008 October 16 (Box 2)
  - Diploma, Honorary Doctorate, University of Tokyo, 2008 October 17 (Box 3)